

# SUDHEERA MADDILA

FAIRFAX, VIRGINIA - 22030 • +1 (571)-307-0553 • sudheera897@gmail.com • LinkedIn

# **SUMMARY**

A passionate Computer Science graduate currently pursuing a master's degree specializing in Machine Learning. Committed to developing a career path and focus on boosting productivity to contribute to organizational success. Background includes a demonstrated work experience of 2+ years in the IT industry.

#### **EDUCATION**

- Master's (2021-2023): MS in CS -Machine Learning concentration, George Mason University.
- B. Tech (2015-2019): Computer Science Engineering, GPA: 8.66/10

#### **PROJECTS**

 MULTI-LINGUAL OFFENSIVE COMMENT IDENTIFICATION-

Developed a machine learning model in Python by using different libraries such as NumPy, Scikit-Learn, NLTK, Stanford NLP & SciPy.

 SMART PARKING MANAGEMENT SYSTEM using IoT-

Developed an algorithmic model in Java and worked on technologies such as Android, HTML, CSS, XML, and PHP.

• INTENTION BASED SCORING using K-means CLUSTERING-

Worked on a data mining model in Python using the unsupervised learning algorithm to perform inspection of an on-line protocol, bug identification, and scoring.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Application Development Analyst**, 06/2019 to 07/2021 **ACCENTURE SOLUTIONS PVT LTD** - Hyderabad, India

- Developed automation bots in RPA technology based on Artificial Intelligence to deploy metaphorical software bots that automate predictable data transition work and interface the back-end systems using internal APIs.
- Worked as an EDI analyst in 'Seeburger' middle-ware integration with SAP expertise to develop new systems for clients, analyze requirements, produce mapping documents, test systems, and establish communication with trading partners.
- Extended support and maintenance for Java applications in line with business.

# Full Stack Development Intern, 05/2018 to 07/2018 MAIN STAY TECH SOLUTIONS PVT LTD - Hyderabad, India

Worked on a J2EE application in Java and Angular JS to augment job-scheduling and job-triggering workflows of their embedded operating systems using 'Quartz Scheduler Framework.'

**IT Intern**, 11/2017 to 12/2017

### VISAKHAPATNAM STEEL PLANT - Visakhapatnam, India

- Worked on an ERP package to support continued procedural and operational developments and integrate SAP systems of a business process.
- Communicated with clients during business meetings and took detailed notes to transcribe for distribution to the entire department.

#### **IT Intern**, 09/2017 to 10/2017

# BLUEFROG MOBILE TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD - Visakhapatnam, India

Beta tested mobile applications and resolved issues by trouble-shooting and debugging programs to ensure functionality and correct errors prior to the official launch.

# **SKILLS**

- Languages: C, C++, Java, Python
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, XML, React, PHP, Angular JS, RPA
- Database: MySQL, Oracle
- Packages: MS-Office
- OS: Windows, Linux, UNIX, iOS
- Characteristic traits: Quick learner, Work Ethic, Technical competency

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Course certification on 'Programming, Data Structures, and Algorithms using C' from IIT-NPTEL, India.
- Certifications for training programs on 'Ethical Hacking and Information Security', 'Android', 'Python Programming' & 'Building Modern Python Applications on AWS'